JIFI RAJFNDRAN



PORTFOLIO

- behance.net/danielrajendran
- in linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

CONTACT

- ✓ daniel.rajendran@gmail.com
- 07708698413
- danonthe.net

OTHER

- twitter.com/danrajendran
- instagram.com/danrajendran

ABOUT

I'm a multi-discipline designer with seven years experience working for fast-paced tech startups in London. Since studying interaction design at university I've cultivated an extremely broad set of skills that cover web, brand, product, and UX design. I have a keen eye for details that doesn't stop me seeing the bigger picture, and whether it be apps, emails, websites, or products, I'm most at home when designing and building things.

EXPERIENCE

DataSift

January 2015 - December 2016

Front-End Developer / UX Designer

- Played an instrumental part in launching web content for our Facebook Topic Data product launch
- Responsible for coding, QA, and maintenance for the marketing site, blog, and helpdesk
- Assited the Product team with UX design and prototyping for a new product offering
- Lead an effort to unify the varying design languages used by Marketing and Product teams

Huddle

January 2010 - December 2015

Lead Web Designer

- Acted as the primary design and development resource for the commercial arm of the company
- Handled design, coding, QA, and maintenance for the marketing site, blog, and helpdesk
- Assisted in a complete rebrand, and then lead one full redesign of the marketing site
- Lead a small team that redesigned the home page and free trial process to increase lead gen 180%

EDUCATION

Goldsmiths. University of London

September 2006 - August 2009

BSc Computing and Interaction Design

Covered a wide range of topics that centered on web design, user experience and interaction design. My final project was a human interface device that could be used to manipulate 3D models in real-time, for use in museums so users could better examine exhibits.

University of Westminster

September 2004 - August 2006

BEng Computer and Networks Engineering

Focused on programming. I transfered during my 2nd year to persue a more design oriented degree.

SKILLS

HTML(4/5), CSS(2/3), PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI **Technology**

WordPress, Jekyll, SalesForce, Mailchimp, Aprimo, Eloqua, Marketo, Google Analytics Systems

Sketch, Marvel, InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, SVN, Git, Fiddler **Applications**

Wireframing, Prototyping, Responsive design, Fluid grids **Process**

Cross-browser compliance, Cross-client compliance, SEO, Print-ready markup Delivery

Other Photo retouching, Photography, Copy writing, Illustration

REFERENCES

Available on request